Guide To the University Of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection ARS.0103
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 10.5" reels, 89 audiotape reel(s)
  - Roussel: Trio, 1955; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; full track] (Box 5, Reel 49)
    Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937. Trio. Coleman Chamber Music audition winners.
    Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937
  - Britten and Pears at the University of Southern California, circa 1949; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; four track] (Box 5, Reel 50)
    Possible content
    Presumed to be the rest of the concert featured on reel 21 in Box 4.
  - Imbrie: Angle of Repose, 1976; 2 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; two track; stereo] (Box 5, Reel 51, Reel 54)
    Imbrie, Andrew, 1921-2007. Angle of repose. Recording is assumed to be of the world premiere production in 1976 at San Francisco Opera. This is based on a letter to the recording engineer, found with reel 51, dated 1976.
    Imbrie, Andrew, 1921-2007
  - Coleman Chamber Music Association, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; quarter-track; dolby] (Box 5, Reel 52)
    Includes a small slip of paper that reads "A.Curtis / Goldberg".
  - Coleman Chamber Music Association, 1956-08-17; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 5, Reel 53)
  - Alice Ehlers lecture recital, 1961-07-15; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 57)
  - Hill: Greenwater. Lovelock: Requiem, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 60)
    Hill, Alfred, 1869-1960. Green water.
    Lovelock, William. Requiem for heroes.
    Hill, Alfred, 1869-1960; Lovelock, William
  - Shostakovich: Symphony No.10, 1976-08-16; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 61)
    Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975. Symphonies, no. 10, op. 93, E minor. Staatskapelle Dresden; Von Karajan, conductor. Salzburg Large Festival Hall.
    Possible additional content
    Another notes with the recording indicate that it might also contain works by Duke Ellington, possibly dubs of 78rpm discs. The spine of the container for the recording also mentions the San Francisco Symphony Orchestra.
    Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975; Staatskapelle Dresden; Karajan, Herbert von
  - Huybrechts: Trio for flute, viola, and piano, 1972-07; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 62)
    Huybrechts, Albert, 1899-1938. Trios, piano, flute, viola. Isselée, flute; Nauwelaers, viola; Rodrigue, piano. Festival of Belgium, 1972. KPFA broadcast.
    Rodrigue, Pierre; Nauwelaers, Roger; Isselée, André; Huybrechts, Albert, 1899-1983
  - Goldberg, Curtis, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; two-track] (Box 6, Reel 63)
  - Moe rejects, 1961-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 64)
  - Phillips: Partita. Honegger: Pastorale d'ete. New friends of old music, circa 1952; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 65)
    Phillips, Burrill. Partita, piano, strings.
    Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955. Pastorale d'été.
    New friends of old music. Los Angeles County Museum. KUSC. August 3, 1952.
    Phillips, Burrill; Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955
  - Kohs: Chamber concerto. Stevens: Quintet. Haieff: Sonata, 1952-07-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 66)
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000. Chamber concerto. University of Southern California's sixth annual Festival of Contemporary Arts. Hancock Auditorium.
    Stevens, Halsey, 1908-1989. Quintet, piano, flute, violin, viola, cello. Kendall, piano; Jacobsen, violin; Schonbach, viola; Deák, cello; Stevens, flute. University of Southern California's sixth annual Festival of Contemporary Arts. Hancock Auditorium.
    Haieff, Alexei, 1914-1994. Sonatas, pianos (2). University of Southern California's sixth annual Festival of Contemporary Arts. Hancock Auditorium.
    Deák, Stephen; Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000; Kendall, Raymond, 1910-1980; Jacobsen, Sascha, 1895-1972; Haieff, Alexei, 1914-1994; Stevens, Roger; Stevens, Halsey, 1908-1989; Schonbach, Sanford
  - Mussorgsky: Boris Godunov, act 4. Hindemith: String trio No.1, circa 1954; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 67)
    Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov. Act 4.
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Trios, violin, viola, cello, no. 2. Reher, Sven, viola; Reher, Kurt, cello. Name of violinist undecipherable. June 6, 1954.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: Counterpoint/Esoteric Records, CPT-523 (Hindemith Sonata for Harp: Zabaleta).
    Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; Reher, Kurt; Reher, Sven; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
  - Falla; Kirchner; Kohs; Mozart, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 68)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 378, B♭ major.
    Kirchner, Leon; Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Gillespie, John; Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946; Wade, Archie; Hutchinson, Clement; Rathbun, Loyd; Schafer, Ralph
  - Hindemith; Leclair; Mozart; Powell; Schumann; Sibelius; Vaughan-Williams, circa 1952-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 69)
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Two duos for clarinet and viola.
    Leclair. Trio sonata in D for viola, clarinet and piano.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Trios, piano, clarinet, viola, K. 498, E♭ major.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Märchenerzählungen
    Powell, John, 1882 – 1963. Rhapsody Negro.
    Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Pelléas et Mélisande. New York Philharmonic, Beecham, conductor.
    Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Group 1.
    New York Philharmonic; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Powell, John, 1882-1963; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957; Vaughan-Williams, Ralph
  - Stravinsky: Three pieces and concertino. Respighi: Suite No.2. Walton: Belshazzar's feast., circa 1952; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 70)
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Pieces, violins (2), viola, cello. [Name of string quartet indecipherable]. September 21, 1952.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Concertino, violins (2), viola, cello.[Name of string quartet indecipherable]. September 21, 1952.
    Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Antiche arie e danze per liuto, no. 2. Vienna State Opera Orchestra, Litschauer, conductor.
    Walton, William, 1902-1983. Belshazzar's feast.
    Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Walton, William, 1902-1983; Wiener Staatsoper. Orchester; Litschauer, Franz, 1903-1972
  - Creston; Debussy; Falla; Fauré; Hahn; Malipiero; Poulenc; Ravel; Satie; Yardumian. Folk music from India, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips] (Box 6, Reel 71)
    Yardumian, Richard. Desolate city. [Name of orchestra indecipherable].
    Creston, Paul, 1906-1985. Threnody. Los Angeles Philharmonic.
    Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Amor brujo. Beal, contralto; Los Angeles Philharmonic.
    Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Poèmes de Baudelaire. Tourel, soprano; [pianist's name indecipherable].
    Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963. Banalités. Voyage à Paris. Tourel, soprano. Another Poulenc song appears to have been performed after this one. However, the title is indecipherable.
    Satie, Erik, 1866-1925. Mélodies (1916). Chapelier. Tourel, soprano.
    Satie, Erik, 1866-1925. Je te veux. Tourel, soprano.
    Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Poème d'un jour. Tourel, soprano.
    Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Vocalise en forme d'habanera. Tourel, soprano.
    Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. Si mes vers avaient des ailes. Tourel, soprano; Reeves, piano.
    Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973. Sonata a cinque. Newell, harp; Stuyvesant Quartet.
    Sanai Gath (Raga Kaphi)
    Religious song from Kerala.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: The first eight recordings made by Andre Kostelanetz and his orchestra.
    Yardumian, Richard; Creston, Paul, 1906-1985; Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946; Beal, Eula, 1919-2008; Tourel, Jennie; Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918; Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963; Satie, Erik, 1866-1925; Fauré, Gabriel, 1845–1924; Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937; Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947; Reeves, George; Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973; Stuyvesant String Quartet
  - Toch: Quartet No.8, 1954-04-25; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 72)
    Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 8, op. 18, D♭ major. New Music Quartet. World premiere. April 25, 1954.
    A newspaper clipping can be found inside the container for this recording that contains a listing for another New Music Quartet peformance on April 12, 1953. There is no indication on either the recording's container or the recording itself however that the recording features this 1953 performance.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: RCA Victor, LCT1029 (Haydn concerto in D, Op.21).
    Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964; New Music String Quartet
  - Dvořák; Haydn; White, circa 1952; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 6, Reel 73)
    Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Quintets, piano, violins (2), viola, cello, op. 81, A major. September 28, 1952.
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, H. III, 76, D minor. Hollywood Quartet. October 5, 1952.
    Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, B. 179, F major. Hollywood Quartet.
    White, Paul. Five minatures. Boston Pops Orchestra.
    Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; White, Paul; Compinsky String Quartet; Compinsky, Sara, 1904?-1992; Hollywood String Quartet; Boston Pops Orchestra
  - Kohs: String quartet. Bartók: Sonata for two pianos. Studies in organ tone, part 2, circa 1953; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 74)
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 1. [Quartet name indecipherable]. November 11, 1953.
    Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945. Sonatas, pianos (2), percussion. [Quartet name indecipherable]. November 13, 1953.
    Studies in organ tone, part 2.
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000; Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945
  - Martin: Le vin herbé. Studies in organ tone, part 1, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 75)
    Martin, Frank, 1890-1974. Vin herbé. Part 4.
    Studies in organ tone, part 1.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: Vox, PL8270 (Stravinsky, Apollon Musagète).
    Martin, Frank, 1890-1974
  - Mozart; Kodaly; Pick-Mangiagalli; Suk. Kostelanetz and Fassett interview, circa 1953-1955; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1.4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 76)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimento in F. Members of the Vienna Octet.
    Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 1, op. 2. Pro Musica String Quartet. Los Angeles Museum. May 3, 1953.
    Pick-Mangiagalli, Riccardo, 1882-1949. Ariette from quartet, Op.18. Pro Musica String Quartet. Los Angeles Museum. May 3, 1953.
    Suk, Josef, 1874-1935. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 1, op. 11, B♭ major. Intermezzo. Pro Musica String Quartet. Los Angeles Museum. May 3, 1953.
    Interview with Kostelanetz and Fassett regarding Japanese music.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Wiener Oktett; Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967; Pick-Mangiagalli, Riccardo, 1882-1949; Suk, Josef; Pro Musica String Quartet; Kostelanetz, Andre, 1901-1980; Fassett, Jim
  - Beethoven: Sonata for violin and piano, Op.96. Mozart: Sonata, K376. Bach: Sonata, BWV 1017, 1952; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 77)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 10, op. 96, G major. Shaprio, violin; Kaufman, piano. December 7, 1952.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 376, F major. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 10, 1952.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1017, C minor. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 10, 1952.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: Period, SPL 568 (Schoenberg, 3 Piano Pieces Op.11: Michael Field).
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827; Shapiro, Eudice; Kaufman, Harry, 1894-1961; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Murray, Alexander
  - Britten: Serenade. Dvorak: New world symphony. Cabrillo Festival 1971, circa 1971-1972; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 7, Reel 78)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Serenade, tenor, horn, string orchestra, op. 31. Best, tenor; Jones, horn; Philadelphia Orchestra, Ormandy, conductor. January 8, 1972.
    Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Philadelphia Orchestra, Ormandy, conductor. January 8, 1972.
    Cabrillo Festival, 1971. Featuring works by Villa Lobos, Chavez, and Poulenc.
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976; Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985; Philadelphia Orchestra; Best, Michael; Jones, Mason
  - Chávez: Three poems. Pisk: Five two part inventions. Berg: Four pieces for clarinet and piano, circa 1953; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 7, Reel 79)
    Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978. Poemas. Mackay, Margery, Mackay, Harper, piano.
    Pisk, Paul Amadeus, 1893-1990. Five two-part inventions.
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935. Stücke, clarinet, piano, op. 5. Ramsey, clarinet; Howe, piano. KUSC broadcast. March 16, 1953.
    Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978; Pisk, Paul Amadeus, 1893-1990; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935; MacKay, Margery, 1925-; Mackay, Harper; Ramsey, Gloria; Howe, James
  - Britten 50th Birthday Concert, 1963; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 80)
    Britten 50th Birthday Concert. BBC broadcast.
  - Britten: Rape of Lucretia, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 82)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Rape of Lucretia. BBC broadcast.
  - Bowles; Dutilleux; Hindemith; Kohs; Petrassi; Prokofiev; Vennard, 1953-03-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 83)
    Petrassi, Goffredo, 1904-2003. Dialogo angelico. Mee, Bourquin, flutes. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Kanonische Sonatine. Mee, Bourquin, flutes. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000. Sonatas, clarinet, piano. Harlow, clarinet; Kaufman, piano. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Uverti︠u︡ra na evreĭskie temy. Bovard String Quartet. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Dutilleux, Henri, 1916-2013. Sonatina, flute, piano. Bourgain, flute; Zimmerman, piano. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Variations on the Riddle Song by graduate student various composers. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Songs by W.M.Vennard, bas of USC. Accompanied by Williams and Koldovsky. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916 – 2000. Five sonnets from fatal interview, Millay. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    Bowles, Paul, 1910–1999. Four songs. Southern California Festival of Contemporary Arts.
    A newspaper clipping found in with this recording suggests that the concert captured on the recording also included a performance of Aaron Copland's Piano Sonata, performed by Athur Satz.
    Petrassi, Goffredo, 1904–2003; Mee, Margaret; Bourquin, Joanne E.; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000; Harlow, Fred; Kaufman, Pearl; Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953; Bovard String Quartet; Dutilleux, Henri, 1916-2013; Zimmerman, Ethel; Bowles, Paul, 1910–1999
  - Haydn; Kirkwood; Mozart; Ravel, circa 1952-1953; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 84)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, violins (2), violas (2), cello, K. 593, D major. Coriolan String Quartet; Kurthy, viola.
    Kirkwood, Antoinette, 1930-2014. Andante from suite for string orchestra, Op.5. Waxman, conductor. Los Angeles Museum. KUSC broadcast. March 8, 1953.
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, H. III, 38, E♭ major. Coriolan String Quartet.
    Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Sonatas, violin, piano. Compinsky, Manuel, violin; Compinsky, Sara, piano. Los Angeles Museum. KUSC broadcast. September 7, 1952.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Coriolan String Quartet; Kurthy, Zoltan; Kirkwood, Antoinette, 1930-2014; Waxman, Franz, 1906-1967; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937; Compinsky, Sara, 1904?-1992; Compinsky, Manuel, approximately1902-1989
  - Mozart: Symphony No.36, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 7, Reel 85)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Symphonies, K. 425, C major. Walter, conductor. Includes recording of rehearsal.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962
  - Kanitz: String trio, Sonata for violin and cello, 1960-01-17; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 86)
    Kanitz, Ernest, 1894-1978. String trio. McKay ensemble. Los Angeles Museum.
    Kanitz, Ernest, 1894-1978. Sonata for violin and cello. McKay ensemble. Los Angeles Museum.
    Kanitz, Ernest, 1894-1978; McKay Ensemble
  - John Scott, folksongs, 1960-05-12; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; stereo] (Box 7, Reel 87)
    Folk songs performed: El matador; Shenandoah; Angelique-o; Southcoast; Riddle song; Take my mother home; La Burrita; Molly Malone; First things.
    Scott, John
  - Chávez; Foss; Kaminsky; Lurkevitch?; Schuler, 1955-1956; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 7, Reel 88)
    Lurkevitch? Mass. CBS Music Festival. 1955.
    Kaminski, Joseph. Israeli sketches. CBS Music Festival. 1955.
    Schuller, Gunther. Symphonies, band, op. 16. New York Philharmonic Society, Mitropoulos, conductor. November 4, 1956.
    Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009. Song of songs. Davis, soprano; New York Philharmonic Society, Mitropoulos, conductor. January 8, 1956.
    Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978. Symphonies, no. 3. New York Philharmonic Society, Chávez, conductor. January 29, 1956.
    Kaminski, Joseph; Schuller, Gunther; New York Philharmonic; Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009; Davis, Ellabelle, 1907-1960; Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978
  - Schumann: Piano concerto. Mozart: Concerto No.19 and 26. Beethoven: Concerto No.1, 1970-1971; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 7, Reel 89)
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Eschenbach, piano; Boston Symphony Orchestra, De Burgos, conductor.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Eschenbach, piano; Boston Symphony Orchestra, Tilson Thomas, conductor. Hannover, Germany. April 1971.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Eschenbach, piano; Boston Symphony Orchestra, Boulez, conductor. Cleveland, OH. July 23, 1970.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, piano, orchestra, K. 537, D major. Eschenbach, piano; Boston Symphony Orchestra, Schermerhorn, conductor. Tanglewood, MA. July 26, 1970. Includes an interview.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, piano, orchestra, K. 459, F major. Eschenbach, piano; Boston Symphony Orchestra.
    Interview. Interviewees names in indecipherable.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 15, C major.
    A newspaper clipping found inside the container for this recording suggest that the recording might also feature a radio broadcast featuring works by Blacher, Prokofiev, W.F.Bach, Soler, Witte, Krop-Freiter, and Rovenstrunck.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856; Eschenbach, Christoph; Frühbeck de Burgos, Rafael; Thomas, Michael Tilson, 1944-; Boulez, Pierre, 1925-; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Schermerhorn, Kenneth; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827; Boston Symphony Orchestra
  - Beethoven: Piano concerto No.2. Hindemith: Nobilissima visione, 1975-1976; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; Dolby] (Box 7, Reel 90)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 19, B♭ major. Eschenbach, piano; Cleveland Orchestra, Maazel, conductor. August 27, 1975.
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Nobilissima visione. San Francisco Symphony, Cleve, conductor. January 23, 1976.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827; Eschenbach, Christoph; Maazel, Lorin, 1930-; Cleveland Orchestra; San Francisco Symphony Orchestra; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Cleve, George, 1936-2015
- Unusual Items, 92 audiotape reel(s)
  - Andriessen; Bordewijk-Roepman; Britten; Cage; Van Hemel; Wildberger, circa 1962; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 1)
    Andriessen, Hendrik, 1892-1981. Trio for oboe, flute, and piano. 1962.
    Bordewijk-Roepman, Johanna, 1892-1971. Impromptu for piano. 1962.
    Hemel, Oscar van, 1892-1981. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 5. 1962.
    Andriessen, Hendrik, 1892-1981. Intermezzo for flute and harp. Barwahser, flute; Berghout, harp.
    Dresden, Sem, 1881-1957. Movement from sonata for flute and harp.
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 1, op. 15. Erlih, violin; BBC Symphony Orchestra, Rosband, conductor. International Society for Contemporary Music, London. 1962.
    Wildberger, Jacques. Music, violins (12), violas (5), cellos (3), double basses (2).
    Cage, John. Variations, no. 3.
    Andriessen, Hendrik, 1892-1981; Bordewijk-Roepman, Johanna, 1892-1971; Hemel, Oscar van, 1892-1981; Berghout, Phia; Barwahser, Hubert; Dresden, Sem, 1881-1957; Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976; Erlih, Devy; BBC Symphony Orchestra; Rosbaud, Hans, 1895-1962; Wildberger, Jacques; Cage, John
  - Mahler: Symphony No.3. Yashiro: Piano sonata, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 22)
    Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Symphonies, no. 3, D minor. Horenstein, conductor.
    Yashiro, Akio, 1929-1976. Sonatas, piano. Yamaoka, piano.
    Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911; Yashiro, Akio, 1929-1976; Horenstein, Jascha
  - Herberidge; Legley; Mi͡askovskiĭ; Nono; Rosseau, circa 1963; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 2)
    Legley, Vic, 1915-1994. Quartet. Belgian Festival. 1963.
    Herberidge. Organ concerto. Belgian Festival. 1963.
    Rosseau, Norbert, 1907-1975. Concertos, orchestra, no. 2. Limburg Symphony Orchestra, Rieu, conductor. Belgian Festival. 1963.
    Mi͡askovskiĭ, N. (Nikolaĭ), 1881-1950. Symphonies, no. 21, op. 51, F♯ minor.
    Nono, Luigi. Omaggio a Emilio Vedova.
    Legley, Vic, 1915-1994; Rosseau, Norbert, 1907-1975; Limburgs Symfonie Orkest; Rieu, André, 1917-1992; Mi͡askovskiĭ, N. (Nikolaĭ), 1881-1950; Nono, Luigi
  - Bach; Baur; Eisler; Fries; Riethmüller, circa 1964; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 5)
    Baur, Jürg. Concertino, flute, oboe, clarinet, string orchestra. Orchestra of the City of Aachen, Kempl, conductor. Musica Viva concert. Aachen, Germany. February, 1964.
    Fries, Herbert. Elergy and sinfonia for clarinet and string orchestra. Orchestra of the City of Aachen, Kempl, conductor. Musica Viva concert. Aachen, Germany. February, 1964.
    Riethmüller, Helmut, 1912-1966. Sinfonia serena. Orchestra of the City of Aachen, Kempl, conductor. Musica Viva concert. Aachen, Germany. February, 1964.
    Eisler, Hanns, 1898-1962. Pieces for orchestra. East Berlin Radio Symphony Orchestra, Koch, conductor.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Suites, string orchestra, BWV 1070, G minor. Berlin Chamber Orchestra, Koch, conductor.
    Baur, Jürg; Städtisches Orchester Aachen; Kempl, Hans Walter; Fries, Herbert; Riethmüller, Helmut, 1912-1966; Eisler, Hanns; Berliner Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Koch, Helmut, 1908-1975; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Kammerorchester Berlin
  - Barber; Moran; Gilbert; Winkler, circa 1962; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 8)
    Amy, Gilbert. Movements, horn, piano; arranged. Warsaw Philharmonic, Markowski, conductor.
    Winkler, Peter, 1943-. Trio for flute, cello and piano. Stroud, flute; Libet, cello; Winkler, piano.